<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Exer 2</string>
    <string name="title">Which Disney Villain Are You?</string>
    <string name="start_name">Start</string>
    <string name="retry_name">Retry</string>
    <string name="blank" />

    <string name="scar">You are Scar!</string>
    <string name="cruella">You are Cruella de Vil!</string>
    <string name="ursula">You are Ursula!</string>
    <string name="chernabog">You are Chernabog</string>
    <string name="tremaine">You are Lady Tremaine!</string>
    <string name="grimhilde">You are Queen Grimhilde!</string>
    <string name="gaston">You are Gaston!</string>
    <string name="hades">You are Hades!</string>
    <string name="jafar">You are Jafar!</string>
    <string name="claude">You are Claude Frollo!</string>
    <string name="desc_scar"> Scar is obviously resentful of Mufasa and Simba’s ownership of the throne, but when he finally murders Mufasa via stampede, banishes Simba via manipulation and gains control of Pride Rock, he actually just destroys the land. Even his Hamlet doppelgänger King Claudius was less ruthless than that. Really, Scar is just full-throttle evil, but at the very least he was elegant enough to providemusical foreshadowing. Really just never trust a lion with an English accent. </string>
    <string name="desc_cruella">While demons are most often associated with head-spinning and excessive vomit, Cruella de Vil did her best impression of a hell beast, while managing to appear just as fabulous as a skeletal high-power fashion editor. She isn’t a calculating villain like the rest in the Disney canon, just an impulsively stylish lady, who really doesn’t mind skinning 101 puppies to look good.</string>
    <string name="desc_ursula">The sea witch of Hans Christian Andersen’s “The Little Mermaid” (upon which Ursula is based) is merely an enabler in Ariel’s eventual tragedy, whereas Disney’s voluptuous reworking comes complete with two eel sidekicks, a self-serving agenda and an evil laugh heftier than a bowl of New England clam chowder. Of course, she tricks Ariel into a terrifically unfair deal, but at least our little mermaid didn’t end up turning into those ambiguous little sea bugs that she just calls “Poor Unfortunate Souls.”</string>
    <string name="desc_chernabog">Chernabog is just, like, literally the stuff nightmares are made of (especially if you were under the age of 8, when you first watched “Fantasia”). His appearance is somewhat brief, but it comes at the climax of the film, represented by what is easily the most terrifyingly sinister theme song of all the Disney villains combined. Basically, the big bog would win versus anyone in a cage fight.</string>
    <string name="desc_tremaine">No super powers here, just one super mean lady. Much like The Abominable Snowman, the wicked stepmother would probably have been much nicer if that dress had a less aggressive neck line (itchy!). She never abuses Cinderella physically, but the extent to which she harasses her psychologically gets pretty creative. Although, minus the whole forcing-her-to-clean-cinders thing, Lady Tremaine had at least some right to be annoyed that Cindy made her own daughters seem even more shrill.</string>
    <string name="desc_jafar">The Royal Vizier of Agrabah is an amoral psychopath. With no understanding of remorse and a penchant for pure evil, he is perhaps more consistently evil than his villainous brethren. Essentially, his entire goal is to trick Jasmine into being his slave queen, only so that he can kill her and take the throne. Yet, despite all of the unabated maleficence, there is something vaguely comical about his sense of humor and enduring flair for sarcasm, executed flawlessly with the help of his sidekick parrot Iago.</string>
    <string name="desc_grimhilde">The Evil Queen is so iconic that she doesn’t really need a name. Probably the best part of her backstory is the frivolity of her Snow White vendetta. She literally destroys some chick’s life, because she wants to be the fairest of them all. Despite the fact that a boyfriend and / or manservant with a penchant for flattery could have avoided the whole mess she caused, the Evil Queen and her penciled-on eyebrows made for a sleek and chilling villain. </string>
    <string name="desc_gaston">Gaston is basically the quintessential bro, which really makes him more aggressively intolerable than horrifying. He works out too much (or at least eats too many raw eggs?) and thinks he is literally “the greatest hunter in the world.” Interestingly enough, he doesn’t seem super evil until much later in the film, when he decides to deliberately incite hysteria and lead a pitchfork mob to “Kill The Beast.” #YOLO #ragespiral #comeatmebro</string>
    <string name="desc_hades">Hades is so campy, it’s easy to forget he’s the god of the underworld, acting as Hercules’ sworn enemy. Really, it’s a challenge to have any character be voiced by James Woods and still make them seem genuinely malevolent, but it works. Despite his grand plot to overthrow Zeus’ throne, Hades takes the shape of a trickster-type character with serious anger management issues. He also gets points for having a theme song that sounds like it cold have been written by Mumford and Sons.</string>
    <string name="desc_claude">“The Hunchback of Notre Dame” was definitively dark for a Disney film, the kind of thing your mom maybe wished she didn’t take you to see in theaters ... and a lot of those sexualized evil undertones / general hellfire was perpetuated by Claude Frollo. Don’t be fooled by the stupid hat, the Minister of Justice thought nothing of locking a baby in an attic and considering burning down “all of Paris” just to find a gypsy that he has a crush on. </string>
</resources>
